Paul Baran Papers M1817
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- PB Invent Date:971213 (Container 256, Folder 29)
  Stylus Alphabet Writing (Drawing)
- PB Invent Date:770001 (Container 256, Folder 30)
  Automatic File Locator (I) (Drawing)
- PB Invent Date:951126 (Container 256, Folder 31)
  Universal Intelligent Woodworking Tool (UIWT) (Description and drawing)
- PB Invent Date:950001 (Container 256, Folder 32)
  Pop-up Antenna (I) (Drawing)
- PB Invent Date:941203 (Container 256, Folder 33)
  Flatwire (I) (Drawing)
- PB Invent Date:910829 (Container 256, Folder 34)
  Electric Power Distribution by Radio (I) (Drawing)
- PB Invent Date:951230 (Container 256, Folder 35)
  Electric Power Meter (i) (Drawing)
- PB Invent Date:950001 (Container 256, Folder 36)
  Buried Electric Meter (I) (Drawing)
- PB Invent Date:991102 (Container 256, Folder 37)
  Great Circle Non-radiator (i) (Drawing)
- PB Invent Date:000108 (Container 256, Folder 38)
  Clip On Power Meter (I) (Drawing)
- PB Invent Date:990411 (Container 256, Folder 39)
  Balloon Antenna (I) (Drawing)
- PB Invent Date:981206 (Container 256, Folder 40)
  Helicopter Antenna (Drawing)
- PB Invent Date:000319 (Container 256, Folder 41)
  Smart File Locator (Written description plus drawings)
- PB Invent Date:970403 (Container 256, Folder 42)
  Remote Power scheme (I) (Information from several sources)
- PB Invent Date:981220 (Container 256, Folder 43)
  Wireless Pur. Distribution (I) (Drawing)
- Telebit Date:890700 (Container 259, Folder 1)
  Financial Statements, July 1989; Board Meeting Agenda, Sept. 14
- Telebit Date:890800 (Container 259, Folder 2)
  Financial Statements, August 1989
- Telebit Date:890900 (Container 259, Folder 3)
  Financial Management Reports, Sept, 1989
- Telebit Date:890900 (Container 259, Folder 4)
  Telebit Corp, Business Plan, Sept. 1989 (draft)
- Telebit Date:891000 (Container 259, Folder 5)
  Financial Management Reports, Oct, 1989
- Telebit Date:891100 (Container 259, Folder 6)
  Financial Management Reports, Nov, 1989
- Telebit Date:891200 (Container 259, Folder 7)
  Financial Management Reports, Dec, 1989
- Telebit Date:900209 (Container 259, Folder 8)
  Telebit Digital Product Options; Financial Relations Board
- Telebit Date:900214 (Container 259, Folder 9)
  Telebit: When Connectivity Counts
- Telebit Date:900216 (Container 259, Folder 10)
  Draft - Registration Statement for the Telebit Corporation initial public offering
- Telebit Date:900300 (Container 259, Folder 11)
  Financial Management Reports, March, 1990
- Telebit Date:900307 (Container 259, Folder 12)
  SEC- Form 1, Registration Statement
- Telebit Date:900307 (Container 259, Folder 13)
  Initial Public Offering - 2,090,000 Shares, Common Stock
- Telebit Date:900308 (Container 259, Folder 14)
  Board of Directors Meeting, March 8, 1990
- Telebit Date:900308 (Container 259, Folder 15)
  Board Meeting Agenda, March 8, 1990; Financial Management Reports, Jan, 1990
- Telebit Date:900330 (Container 259, Folder 16)
  Proposed Changes to the Rules under Section 16, Securities Exchange Act, 1934 (Wilson, Sonsini)
- Telebit Date:900413 (Container 259, Folder 17)
- Telebit Date:900425 (Container 259, Folder 18)
- Telebit Date:900426 (Container 259, Folder 19)
  Underwriting Agreement - 2,090,000 Shares, Common Stock (Cowen & Co)
- Telebit Date:900500 (Container 259, Folder 20)
  Financial Management Reports, May, 1990
- Telebit Date:900510 (Container 259, Folder 21)
  Board of Directors Meeting, May 10, 1990
- Telebit Date:900515 (Container 259, Folder 22)
  Financial Management Reports, April, 1990
- Telebit Date:900603 (Container 259, Folder 23)
  Price/Value Information
- Telebit Date:900608 (Container 259, Folder 24)
  TBIT Stock Pricing Contest; Bingham's notes from CCITT briefing; Product Development Outline
- Telebit Date:900716 (Container 259, Folder 25)
  Second Quarter Results; "Modem Butterfly"
- Scrapbook Date:661030 (Container 262, Folder 1)
  Copy of C&C Citation for Seminal Architectural Contributions to Arpane, Internet, WWW
- Scrapbook Date:670401 (Container 262, Folder 2)
  Urban Node in the Information Network, by PB and M. Greenberger
- Scrapbook Date:671201 (Container 262, Folder 3)
  AMA 1967 Winter Conference, "Changing Marketing Systems" by PB
- Scrapbook Date:840523 (Container 262, Folder 4)
  Trust Agreement between Paul and Evelyn Baran
- Scrapbook Date:850720 (Container 262, Folder 5)
  Misc: Mozart Program, Benjamin Franklin Award pictures, Drexel Alumni Profile (PB)
- Scrapbook Date:890817 (Container 262, Folder 6)
  UCLA Act One, a symposium on very high speed information networks
- Scrapbook Date:900319 (Container 262, Folder 7)
  Telebit News Release: "PB, Telebit Founder, Named Chairman of Board", B&W Photo
- Scrapbook Date:900501 (Container 262, Folder 8)
  The Institute: IEEE Board of Directors Announced (includes PB)
- Scrapbook Date:910601 (Container 262, Folder 9)
  Marconi International Fellowship Award
- Scrapbook Date:970602 (Container 262, Folder 10)
  PB Papers (clear copies) - "Darwin Among Machines," "IEEE", "Inventing the Internet," "On Dist. Comm"
- Scrapbook Date:981230 (Container 262, Folder 11)
  PB's letter to Frank Kuo re: nomination for IEEE Medal of Honor. Full background info.
- Scrapbook Date:990602 (Container 262, Folder 12)
  Folder of Reference Papers for Histories, Articles, etc. Also ltr. to Andrew Gurney
- Scrapbook Date:990623 (Container 262, Folder 13)
  Ltr. To Judith Semas with background info. on PB
- Scrapbook Date:010001 (Container 262, Folder 14)
  D. W. Davis paper of Beg. of Packet Switching; W. H. Ware Introduction to Davies' Paper
- Scrapbook Date:020001 (Container 262, Folder 15)
  Various PB Resumes
- Scrapbook Date:050001 (Container 262, Folder 16)
  Publicity Packet of Material on PB (CV, List of Awards, Info. On Packet Switching, Articles)
- Scrapbook Date:060314 (Container 262, Folder 17)
  PB List of Publications
- Scrapbook Date:070001 (Container 262, Folder 18)
  National Medal of Technology, 2007 Nomination Form
- Scrapbook Date:070404 (Container 262, Folder 19)
  The Almanac, "Atherton's PB Defined the Landscape for Modern Communications Networks"
- Marconi Date:910725 (Container 263, Folder 1)
  Marconi in Silicon Valley (PB's handwritten notes)
- Marconi Date:920901 (Container 263, Folder 2)
  Marconi Book Typed (V.2) in Progress (PB's corrections and notes)
- PacketTech Date:870109 (Container 263, Folder 3)
  Packet Technologies Closing File - Fenwick, Davis & West
- Marconi Date:910707 (Container 263, Folder 4)
  PB discusses start-up Ventures, compares Marconi's characteristics needed for success
- Misc. Date:951219 (Container 263, Folder 6)
  PB's Companies, B-Hype
- Telebit Date:870921 (Container 264, Folder 1)
  Product Planning Report
- Telebit Date:910814 (Container 264, Folder 2)
  First in Dial-Up Internetworking
- Telebit Date:910826 (Container 264, Folder 3)
  Cohen & Ostler: "Attorney Client Privileged Communication" (Re: Hayes/Heatherington)
- Telebit Date:921204 (Container 264, Folder 4)
  1993 Manufacturing Plan
- Telebit Date:930200 (Container 264, Folder 5)
  Tele "Bits" - Netblazer 2.0 Release
- Telebit Date:930212 (Container 264, Folder 6)
  Agreement & Plan of Merger & Reorganization - by and among Telebit
- Telebit Date:930224 (Container 264, Folder 7)
  Financial Management Report, Dec. 1992 (includes several Financial Reports)
- Telebit Date:930217 (Container 264, Folder 8)
  TidBITS #163 Modems
- Telebit Date:930507 (Container 264, Folder 9)
  Joint Proxy statement - Telebit Prospectus
- Telebit Date:930527 (Container 264, Folder 10)
  Telebit Netblazer PN & NetBlazer ACS
- Telebit Date:930602 (Container 264, Folder 11)
  Telebit Completes Merger with Octocom System; Board Meeting April 1, 1993
- Telebit Date:930709 (Container 264, Folder 12)
  Restrictions on Securities Transactions; Tentative Settlement of Litigation
- Telebit Date:930900 (Container 264, Folder 13)
  The Telebit Worldblazer Modem: It Transmits Where Others Fail
- Telebit Date:950605 (Container 264, Folder 14)
  Telebit Announces Aggressive New Product Designed to Expand Presence in Global Remote Network Access
- Misc. Date:910801 (Container 265, Folder 2)
  Telebit: Financial Management Report, August, 1991
- Misc. Date:910816 (Container 265, Folder 3)
  Telebit: "Developing Countries' Interest in Data Modems: Standardization Issues"
- Misc. Date:911001 (Container 265, Folder 4)
  Telebit: Financial Management Report, October 1991
- Misc. Date:911001 (Container 265, Folder 5)
  Telebit: "Operating Plan, October 1991"
- Misc. Date:911001 (Container 265, Folder 6)
  Telebit: Email from Kramlich, "Security Ownership of Management" and other issues
- Misc. Date:911101 (Container 265, Folder 7)
  Telebit: Financial Management Report, Nov. 1991
- Misc. Date:911015 (Container 265, Folder 8)
  Telebit: PB's letter to Shareholders
- Misc. Date:911125 (Container 265, Folder 9)
  Telebit: Letter from Steyermark to PB
- Misc. Date:911201 (Container 265, Folder 10)
  Telebit: Management Incentive Plan - Manager's Manual, 1992 Plan
- Misc. Date:911231 (Container 265, Folder 11)
  Telebit: Report on U.S. Robotics
- Misc. Date:920101 (Container 265, Folder 12)
  Telebit: "Tele "Bits" - 1st Anniversary Edition
- Misc. Date:920114 (Container 265, Folder 13)
  Telebit: Telebit Names President & CEO, Michael Ballard
- Misc. Date:920123 (Container 265, Folder 14)
  Telebit: Letter from Denis Aull regarding HDSL articles
- Misc. Date:920213 (Container 265, Folder 15)
  Telebit: Agenda for Board of Directors meeting, Feb. 13, 1992
- Misc. Date:920304 (Container 265, Folder 16)
  Telebit: Confidential Memo regarding Hayes Proposal
- Misc. Date:920316 (Container 265, Folder 17)
  Telebit: Financial Management Report, January, 1992
- Misc. Date:920201 (Container 265, Folder 18)
  Telebit: Financial Management Report, February, 1992
- Misc. Date:920401 (Container 265, Folder 19)
  Telebit: Memorandum of Understanding and Service Agreement between Telebit and Grand Duchy of Luxembourg
- Misc. Date:920402 (Container 265, Folder 20)
  Telebit: Letter from C.J. Good Financial Analysis; 3rd Quarter Results; other memos
- Misc. Date:920622 (Container 265, Folder 21)
  Telebit: "Telebit Appoints Senior Vice President of Sales and Marketing"
- Misc. Date:750626 (Container 265, Folder 22)
  Term/Comprint: Articles of Incorporation (Wilson, Mosher & Sonsini)
- Misc. Date:761111 (Container 265, Folder 23)
  Term/Comprint: Business Plan - the Electronic Mailbox Company
- Misc. Date:761206 (Container 265, Folder 24)
  Term/Comprint: The Convergence of Computing & Telecommunications System; Print Samples
- Misc. Date:770101 (Container 265, Folder 25)
  Term/Comprint: Photographs
- Misc. Date:770101 (Container 265, Folder 26)
  Term/Comprint: Printer Samples
- Misc. Date:770426 (Container 265, Folder 27)
  Term/Comprint: SRI Visit to Examine Plain Paper Printing Technique; SRI-CableData-Savin Agreement
- Misc. Date:770426 (Container 265, Folder 28)
  Term/Comprint: Further Notice of Proposed Rulemaking (before the FCC)
- Misc. Date:770426 (Container 265, Folder 29)
  Term/Comprint: Comprint 912 - Product Review
- Misc. Date:770426 (Container 265, Folder 30)
  Term/Comprint: Letter to Olson from Parkert Regarding Stock Issuance to Employees
- Misc. Date:770510 (Container 265, Folder 31)
  Term/Comprint: Prod. Proto, Drawings
- Misc. Date:770512 (Container 265, Folder 32)
  Term/Comprint: Letter from Datatrol re: Licensing Agreement (TERMCOM Model 201)
- Misc. Date:770608 (Container 265, Folder 33)
  Term/Comprint: Ltr. From Butler asso re: Low Cost Portable Terminals after Completion of Licensing
- Misc. Date:770806 (Container 265, Folder 34)
  Term/Comprint: Plain paper, silver sample
- Misc. Date:770917 (Container 265, Folder 35)
  Term/Comprint: Invention for manufacturing multi-color ribbons required for color printing
- Misc. Date:771102 (Container 265, Folder 36)
  Term/Comprint: Operating Plan (implication of funding Termcom at $1 million)
- Misc. Date:771102 (Container 265, Folder 37)
  Term/Comprint: Paper Samples
- Misc. Date:780206 (Container 265, Folder 38)
  Term/Comprint: Financial Mistake, Ltr. To Allstate Ins. & Mayfield Fund
- Misc. Date:791001 (Container 265, Folder 39)
  Electronic Business, "Comprint aims its low-cost printer at industrial and retail markets"
- Misc. Date:791001 (Container 265, Folder 40)
  Term/Comprint: Progress Report from General Partners of ICI Edward McGrath & Co.
- Misc. Date:791001 (Container 265, Folder 41)
  Term/Comprint: Texas Instruments - 780 Series Electronics Data Terminal Family
- Misc. Date:791026 (Container 265, Folder 42)
  Term/Comprint: Printing samples
- Misc. Date:791108 (Container 265, Folder 43)
  Term/Comprint: "Portable TTY Termal Cuts Data Entry Steps in Half"
- Misc. Date:791203 (Container 265, Folder 44)
  Term/Comprint: The OEM Computer Newspaper, "Manufactures Gearing Up to market Electro-Resistive Printers
- Misc. Date:791231 (Container 265, Folder 45)
  Term/Comprint: Comments on Dec. Financial Statements Balance Sheet, Cash & Bank Position
- Misc. Date:800114 (Container 265, Folder 46)
  Term/Comprint: Computer Business News, enhanced version of Comprint Model 912 printer
- Misc. Date:800118 (Container 265, Folder 47)
  Term/Comprint: Memorandum of Understanding between CableData Partners & CableData Asso.
- Misc. Date:800125 (Container 265, Folder 48)
  Term/Comprint: Loan Agreement - Comprint notes to VC's plus demand note
- Misc. Date:801009 (Container 265, Folder 49)
  Term/Comprint: Agreement to Michael Long from Gordon Russell, Capital Management Services
- Misc. Date:801202 (Container 265, Folder 50)
  Term/Comprint: Letter to Gordon Russell and Evaluation by Ronald Casentini
- Telebit Date:840105 (Container 266, Folder 1)
  Telebit Marketing Notes
- Telebit Date:850108 (Container 266, Folder 2)
  Financial Management Reports, Jan, 1985
- Telebit Date:850326 (Container 266, Folder 3)
  Board Meeting, March 26, 1985
- Telebit Date:850331 (Container 266, Folder 4)
- Telebit Date:860800 (Container 266, Folder 5)
  Second Annual PC Magazine Award for Technical Excellence (Telebit)
- Telebit Date:860711 (Container 266, Folder 6)
  Telebit Presentation Highlights
- Telebit Date:920618 (Container 266, Folder 7)
  Telebit in the News (many articles June - August, 1992)
- Telebit Date:920701 (Container 266, Folder 8)
  Financial Management Reports, July, 1992
- Telebit Date:920813 (Container 266, Folder 9)
  Board Meeting, Aug. 13, 1992
- Telebit Date:921019 (Container 266, Folder 10)
  Modum Competitive Analysis (Summary of Findings)
- Telebit Date:921020 (Container 266, Folder 11)
  Board Meeting, Oct. 20, 1992
- PB FIles 4080-4090 Awards (Container 268)
- Metricom Date:850120 (Container 269, Folder 1)
  Status Snapshot; hardware & software development; move; funding; marketing (hand-writing)
- Metricom Date:850917 (Container 269, Folder 2)
  Purchase order; Southern Calif. Edison
- Metricom Date:860120 (Container 269, Folder 3)
  Status Snapshot; hardware & software development; move; funding; marketing
- Metricom Date:860201 (Container 269, Folder 4)
  Company philosophy: what's failed, what's new, unique skills, etc.
- Metricom Date:860701 (Container 269, Folder 5)
  IEEE Mag: "Communications and the Law" (Newman)
- Metricom Date:861210 (Container 269, Folder 6)
  Agenda Dec 10, 1986 (includes minutes, financials, progress report, etc.)
- Metricom Date:870122 (Container 269, Folder 7)
  Monthly Financial Report plus unaudited year-end (Hasenbank)
- Metricom Date:870122 (Container 269, Folder 8)
  Job search (for president) - discussion draft
- Metricom Date:870209 (Container 269, Folder 9)
  Why Prudent VC's Capitalists Should Avoid Funding Metering & Control Communication Ventures for the Elec. Utility Industry 269 10 870301 Metricom Research Newsletter: Edison's New Research Focus - the Customer"
- Metricom Date:870601 (Container 269, Folder 11)
  Cooley Godward - shareholders conversion of Dilworth stock purchase
- Metricom Date:870601 (Container 269, Folder 12)
  Heidrick & Struggles - recommendation for Bob Dilworth
- Metricom Date:870610 (Container 269, Folder 13)
  Minutes Board Meeting, June 10, 1987
- Metricom Date:870701 (Container 269, Folder 14)
  Monthly letter Progress Report #12, period June 1987
- Metricom Date:870702 (Container 269, Folder 15)
  Monthly Financial Report, June 1987 (Hasenbank)
- Metricom Date:870708 (Container 269, Folder 16)
  Discussion draft agreement with Mission Venture Capital
- Metricom Date:870710 (Container 269, Folder 17)
  Discussion draft agreement with Mission Venture Management
- Metricom Date:870731 (Container 269, Folder 18)
  SEC Invoice Backup for July, 1987 (includes SCE Contact Accum Invoices)
- Metricom Date:870916 (Container 269, Folder 19)
  Board Minutes, Sept. 16, 1987
- Metricom Date:871001 (Container 269, Folder 20)
  Monthly letter Progress Report #15, period Sept. 1987
- Metricom Date:871015 (Container 269, Folder 21)
  Memo to Board and Investors; Monthly Financial Report, Sept, 1987
- Metricom Date:880105 (Container 269, Folder 22)
  Townsend & Townsend, ISI Work - Packet Routing Protocol
- Metricom Date:880209 (Container 269, Folder 23)
  Meter Sensor Improvements, hand-drawings
- Metricom Date:880805 (Container 269, Folder 24)
  Metricom Common Stock Distribution (confidential)
- Metricom Date:890323 (Container 269, Folder 25)
  Merrill Lynch Capital Markets - Descriptive memorandum (binder)
- Metricom Date:901113 (Container 269, Folder 26)
  Kalkwarf's Time at Metricom
- Metricom Date:930202 (Container 269, Folder 27)
  Letter from PB to John Hanes re: Board resignation
- Metricom Date:930208 (Container 269, Folder 28)
  Confidential Directors Meeting regarding Dilworth
- Metricom Date:930406 (Container 269, Folder 29)
  Board Meeting, April 6 1993; Employee Stock Options
- Metricom Date:939624 (Container 269, Folder 30)
  Board Agenda June 24, 1993; Feb. Minutes
- Metricom Date:930706 (Container 269, Folder 31)
  List of Potential Directors for Metricom (Bond)
- Metricom Date:930909 (Container 269, Folder 32)
  Cooley Godward - Registration rights of Metricom
- Metricom Date:940207 (Container 269, Folder 33)
  Newton Minow - resume and background
- Metricom Date:940322 (Container 269, Folder 34)
  Letter from Frank Griffith, thanking PB for kind words at Board Meeting
- Metricom Date:940511 (Container 269, Folder 35)
  Pennsylvania merchant Group, Summary and Investment Option
- Topics 1020-1406 box 2 (Container 270)
- Telebit (Container 273)
  Chronological
- Publications&Ref Date:611201 (Container 274, Folder 1)
  13 entries, 1953 to Dec. 8, 1961
- Publications&Ref Date:620301 (Container 274, Folder 2)
  8 entries, March 1962 to August 21, 1963
- Publications&Ref Date:640206 (Container 274, Folder 3)
  6 entries, Feb. 6, 1964 to August 1964
- Publications&Ref Date:640801 (Container 274, Folder 4)
  4 entries, Aug. 1964 to Aug. 1964
- Publications&Ref Date:640801 (Container 274, Folder 5)
  17 entries, Aug. 1964 to Dec. 21, 1966
- Telebit (Container 276)
  One-third empty
- Telebit (Container 277)